The border is just another line to cross.
Sicario is a action, crime, thriller film directed by Denis Villeneuve.
An idealistic FBI agent is enlisted by a government task force to aid in the
escalating war against drugs at the border area between the U.S.
and Mexico.
Kate Macer, played by Emily Blunt.
Alejandro Gillick, played by Benicio del Toro.
Matt Graver, played by Josh Brolin.
Dave Jennings, played by Victor Garber.
Ted, played by Jon Bernthal.
Reggie Wayne, played by Daniel Kaluuya.
Sicario is a 2015 American action crime thriller film directed by Denis Villeneuve, written by Taylor
Sheridan in his screenwriting debut and starring Emily Blunt, Benicio del Toro, and Josh Brolin.
The film follows a principled FBI special agent who is enlisted by a government task
force to bring down the leader of a powerful and brutal Mexican drug cartel.
Sicario was selected to compete for the Palme d'Or
at the 2015 Cannes Film Festival.
It began a limited release in the United States on September 18, 2015,
followed by a nationwide release on October 2, 2015.
Sicario received praise for its cast performances, writing,
direction, musical score and cinematography.
The film was nominated for Best Cinematography, Best Original Score,
and Best Sound Editing at the 88th Academy Awards.
It also earned BAFTA nominations for Best Supporting Actor,
Best Cinematography, and Best Film Music.
Its sequel, Sicario: Day of the Soldado, directed by
Stefano Sollima, was released on June 29, 2018.
A third film, titled Sicario: Capos, is in development.
The film is the first installment of writer Taylor Sheridan's American
Frontier Trilogy, proceeding Hell or High Water and Wind River.
The film explores themes of mission, assassin, central
intelligence agency (cia), mexico, corruption.
The tone is dark and intense.